欢迎来到地牢
Ome to the dungeon.
为什么FBI总是把太平间放在
Why do the fbi always stick their morgues
他们能找到的最阴森的地下室里?
in the most depressing basement they can find?
别那么瞧不起别人 Bones
Don't be such a snob,bones.
不是谁都能在造价几百万的实验室里工作
Okay,not everyone gets to play in a multi-million-dollar lab,
你想 还有天窗
you know,with skylights...
这是因为 作为一个社会团体 我们需要把死亡隐藏起来
it's because,as a society,we feel the need to hide death away.
那些和死人打交道的人被看成是怪胎
The people who deal with the dead are viewed as freaks.
我不知道这个是否就是 停尸房会是这样的原因
Yeah. I don't know if it's the basement thing,
但是你即将见到的那个人-- Harry--他有一点被扭曲了
but this guy you're about to meet-- harry--he's a bit twisted.
你可能认为我在工作时是一种匆忙的状态
You probably think I get some kind of rush when I work,
就像是 不知为何心里痒痒那种
that I'm somehow titillated.
注意用词 Bones 注意用词
choice of words,bones,choice of words.
Booth探员
agent booth.
Harry Tepper来见见Jeffersonian的
Harry tepper,meet dr. Temperance brennan
Temperance Brennan博士
from the jeffersonian.
我看过她的档案
I've read her.
你好
Hello.
她很棒
She's good.
也读过你的小说
Read your novel,too.
那个女英雄很好斗
The heroine's very aggressive.
Harry 你是不是想 ?
Harry,you want to...?
好吧 大家来见见Ted Macy 尸体在国家公园被找到
Okay,everybody,meet ted macy.Body was found in a national park.
当地验尸官下的结论是某种意外溺死
Local coroner wrote it off as some kind of an accidental drowning,
但是我们得调查联邦土地上的 每一起死亡
but you see,we have tonvestigate every death on federal land.
通过我的检查 我发现他的喉咙被压碎了
During my examination,I found he had a crushed larynx.
那看起来不是意外
That didn't seem accidental.
这是具有皮肉的尸体
This is a corpse with skin.
她很棒
She is good.
为什么我在这儿? 你知道我不跟皮肉打交道的
Why am I here?You know i don't work with the skin.
放松点 Bones 我带你来不是检查这具尸体的
Relax,bones.I didn't bring you here to examine the body.
我想让你看看他们 在他手心里找到的东西
I want you to see what they found in his hand.
Harry 那个骨头呢?
Harry,the bone?
那是什么?
What is that?
是节指骨
It's a phalanx.
手指骨 还以为她会知道
Finger bone.Figured she'd know that.
我知道任何一个有能力的医学检查者
Yeah,I'd figure any competent medical examiner
都应该知道不要损伤证物 这是来苏尔水(消毒剂)吗?
would know not to compromise evidence.Is this lysol ic?
我们用它来净化残留的污垢
We use it to decontaminate remains.
你是想要把骨膜从骨头表面弄掉
Are you trying to break down the periosteal surface of the bone,
破坏掉骨髓? 你有没有稀释过这个?
wreak havoc on the marrow?Did you even dilute this?
Bones 什么?!
Bones...what?!
你移除了骨头上的微粒和痕迹
You've removed particulates and trace elements
那些有可能带我们找到凶手的东西
that could potentially lead us to his killer.
你是头一天干这行么?
Is this your first day on the job?
下个月就18年了
18 years next month.
她太激动了
She's intense.
印第安人
Native american.
英国殖民者
British colonial.
美国革命 嘿 我们在干嘛?
American revolutionary.Hey,what are we playing?
Brennan博士 证据毁灭者来了
Dr. Brennan,the destroyer of evidence is here.
呃 我假定那是个笑话 这样大家都不会受伤害
Okay,I assume that's a joke,so nobody gets hurt.
Harry真的把这块骨头搞砸了?
Did harry really mess up that bone?
他溶解了所有生长在表面的微粒
He dissolved any traces of ingrained particulates on the surface,
但我们还是能够保留下来 一些有价值的特性
but we were still able to save some valuable attributes.
好比是?
Like what?
在骨膜下表面的骨质疏松与 硬化的结合地带
Alternating sclerotic and porotic areas on subperiosteal surface
有东西证明了不管是谁 他曾经经受了三期梅毒的折磨
demonstrates that whoever this was suffered from tertiary syphilis.
三期梅毒 那是最遭的
Tertiary syphilis.,that's the worst.
在17世纪它是很常见的疾病
It was a common ailment in the 17th century.
正是这块骨头的年代
Which is where the bone dates from.
你说什么?
Say what?
我们做了碳14年代鉴定
We ran a radiocarbon dating test.
这个手指的历史超过了300年
The finger's over 300 years old.
它是该地区相当独特的发现
It's a unique find for the area.
我准备换成法国捕兽者了
I'm going to change to french trapper.
你不能改变你的选择
You can't change yours.
Booth 他们在哪找到受害者的?
Booth,where did they find the victim?
他们从一个联邦海滨保留地的 什么旅游胜地小镇运来的:
They shipped him over from some resort town next to a federal seaside reserve:
Assateague岛
Assateague island.
就是有藏宝坑的那个地方
That's where the money pit is.
藏宝坑?
Money pit?
据传说 Assateague岛是黑胡子 埋藏他的宝藏的地方
Legend is,assateague island is where blackbeard buried his treasure.
300年来 人们一直在尝试找到它
For 300 years,people have been trying to find it.
他们挖了大概150英尺 但什么也没有找到
They've dug it out to something like 150 feet,but they've found nothing.
每次他们靠近的时候
Every time they come close,
就会触发一个挡板 然后海水灌满了深坑
they trigger a baffle that floods the pit with sea water.
傻瓜陷阱 酷
Booby traps.Cool.
尸体在一个发掘现场被发现
The body was found at a dig site.
这是让那个宝藏显得不再仅是一个传说的 第一个实在的证据
This is the first concrete evidence that the treasure is more than a legend.
我敢打赌这是来自那些埋下宝藏的人 中的某一个
I'll bet this is from one of the men who buried the treasure.
纯粹是猜想
Pure conjecture.
海盗
Pirate.
海盗? 海盗?
Pirate?Pirate?
它是个海盗的
It's a pirate.
"你不能改变你的选择"
"You can't change yours."
等等 所以说那个受害者 找到了宝藏存在的证据
Wait,so the victim finds evidence that the treasure exists.
另外有人想要霸占全部财宝
Somebody else wants it all for themselves.
那当然 那是个不错的谋杀动机
That's certainly...that's a good motive for murder.
我们得去那个发掘现场 我很乐意帮忙
We got to get to that dig sited.I'll be glad to help.
没事儿 我-我能搞定
That's okay. I-I can handle it.
嘿 哥们儿 分享财宝
Come on,man,share the wealth.
我们在寻找答案 Jack 不是宝藏
We're looking for answers,jack,not treasure.
你真的以为那下面有宝藏?
Do you really think that treasure exists down there?
你怎么看?
What do you think?
你们在笑什么?
Why are you guys smiling?
海盗!
Pirates!
那是男人的事 甜心
It's a guy thing,sweetie.
是那个死者 Macy 主导这个发掘的?
so,the dead guy,macy,ran the dig?
和他的搭档 Hardewicke
With his partner,hardewicke.
他们是被某个想烧钱的家伙雇佣的
They were hired by anyone with money to burn.
什么 人们会做这种事?
What,people would do that?
一个健全的人去寻找宝藏?
Sane people look for treasure?
那不就是考古学家干的事么?
Well,isn't that what archeologists do?
考古学家是运用证据
Archeologists are scientists
来做为他们勘探的基础的人
who use evidence on which to base their explorations,
而不是那些人在十岁时看过的海盗电影
not some pirate movie they saw when they were ten.
耶 呃 那个 嗯 我们找到的 有300年历史的骨头在某种程度上
Yeah,well,that,uh,300-year-old bone that we just found sort of,
让事情改变了 不是吗 伙计?
changes things now,doesn't it there,matey?
那儿的犯罪现场发生了什么?
What's going on over there the crime scene?
那是为什么我停下了 Branson Rose在那里
That's why i stop,that's Branson Rose is back there.
市长告诉我让他进去
The mayor told me to let him in.
Branson Rose赞助了这个发掘?
Branson rose is funding this dig?
两年了 但我听说他在撤资了
Has been for two years.But I heard he was pulling out.
好吧 谢谢 我会从这儿接手
All right,thanks.I'll take it from here.
当然
Sure.
谁是Branson Rose?
Who's branson rose?
一个亿万富翁探险家
The billionaire adventurer.
他用他的财富为军队制造飞行器
You know,he made his fortune making aircraft for the military.
他掌控了大约半个世界
He owns abt the world.
他就是那个搞环游世界的真人秀的人 还有
He's the guy who has that reality show that goes all over the world and...
还是没有电视? 我为什么要操心啊?
still no tv?Why do I even bother?
你不能现在撤资 Rose先生 我们有合同
You can't pull out now,mr. Rose.we got a contract.
那你可以告我但我不认为 你有可以打倒我的实力
so you can consue but i don't think i've got the resouse to take me on
Rose先生 我们刚刚突破了200英尺!
mr. Rose,we just broke 200 feet!
现在你撤资的话你肯定会错过什么好东西的
Now you pull out now you must miss something.
这话我已经听了两年了 停下来 把东西装到我的卡车上!
n hearing that fortwo years,get f and load my gear!
打扰一下?
Excuse me?
Rose先生 Macy-- 他知道 他感觉到了 那些衣服!
Mr. Rose,macy--he knew it.He felt it.These clothes!
两年了 两百万美元
two years,twllion dollars,
那下面什么都没有 Giles Macy 死得一文不值
there's nothing down there,giles.Macy died for nothing.
FBI! 你们全都被捕了!
Fbi! You're all under arrest!
天哪 Bones 你不用说这个的 我是管事的人
Come on,bones,you don't get to say that.I'm the one with the badge.
现在FBI也卷进来了?
The fbi's involved now?
呃 是的 在联邦领土上的谋杀-- 我们希望- 四处看看
Oh,yeah. You know,murdern deral land--we like to,poke around a little.
谋杀?
Murder?
是的 谋杀
Yeah,murder.
你说那是个意外的
You said it was an accident.
我就是那么认为的
That's what I thought.
哦 我的上帝啊
Oh,my god...
他发现了什么了
he found something.
把我的东西放回去 现在!
Put my stuff back now!
到底Macy找到了什么 竟然会招致杀身之祸?
What did macy find that would be worth killing him for?
1832年 一个六人寻宝小组被杀了
In 1832,a team of six men looking for the treasure were killed
当他们正在挖掘的一个坑道坍塌的时候
when a shaft they were digging collapsed.
黑胡子的诅咒 兄弟
Blackbeard's curse,man.
诅咒? 我们是科学家
A curse?We're scientists.
看看这个 1902年 两个人在挖掘时消失了尸体从未被找到
Look at this. 1902.Two men disappeared while digging.Never found their bodies.
哦 那真是很有诅咒的味道
Oh,that's very cursey.
所以你相信海盗?
So you believe in pirates?
海盗不是圣诞老人 Zack 他们确实存在
Pirates aren't santa,zack.They did exist.
他们确实拥有宝藏 他们确实把它埋起来了
They did have treasures,and they did bury it.
你知道吗 在六岁时我有过一个眼罩
You know,I had an eye patch when I was six.
谁没有呢 我的朋友? 谁没有?
Who didn't,my friend?Who didn't?
不用像教小孩子一样带我
It's not necessary to lead me like a child.
我不希望再有更多的证据被毁坏
I'd rather not have any more evidence compromised.
你把我的胳膊拽的太紧了
You're squeezing my arm very tightly.
对不起
Sorry.
不 不用 没事儿
No,no,it's okay.
你可以把它交给Hodgins 博士
You can give it to dr. Hodgins.
这是什么?
What is this?
从Ted Macy的胃和肺里收集的泥土和水
Soil and water collected from ted macy's throat and lungs.
他被发现时穿着干西装漂在坑道顶部
He was found floating in his dry suit at the top of the shaft.
好了 我需要你来做你的"脏活儿"
All right,you know what?We need you to do your dirt thing.
你知道 把那些粘土和罪案相匹配
You know,match the slime to the crime,
确定那就是他被杀的地方
make sure that's where he was killed.
我要看受害者骨骼的X光片
I'd like to look at x rays of the victim's skeleton.
- 真专横 - 别那么说
Bossy.Do not go there.
本着要把事情搞清楚的精神
In the interest of being thorough,
我要确定他是死在坑道上面的 还是在下面死了漂上来的
I need to determine if he died at the top or died at the bottom and floated up.
我需要各个层次的泥土样本
I need silt abstracts from both levels.
行 我们会帮你搞到的
Fine. We'll get those for you.
不 不 不 那种土壤看起来像是一种
No,no. No.The soil looks like an odd mixture of clay,
粘土 长石 辉石的混合物
plagioclase feldspar,pyroxene...
我真的不能信任任何人 可以正确地收集到这些样本
I really wouldn't trust anyone else to harvest the samples properly.
你就是想去探宝
You just want to look for treasure.
我是一个严肃的科学家仅仅是 在努力把我的工作做到最好
I am a serious scientist merely trying to do my job as well as possible.
那个坑道有超过200英尺深 你知道的
That shaft is over 200 feet deep,you know.
需要专业的潜水员来做这个
It requires an experienced diver.
我是个有执照的潜水者 那意味着我可以下到200英尺以下
I am a certified cave diver,which means I can go deeper than 200 feet.
我曾经潜过Mayan Blue Dos Ojos Tortuga
I dove mayan blue,dos ojos,tortuga...
有去过Naharon 吗?
ever dive naharon?
一次
Once.
我命名了Naharon
I named naharon.
哦 那你怎么能对我说不呢?
Well,then how can you say no to me?
好吧 但仅限于收集泥土样本
Okay.But just to collect soil samples.
当然了
Of course.
呃 你也会潜水?
So,you dive,too?
我有的是时间因为我没有电视看
I have the time because i don't own a tv.
那么你要穿一件橡胶衣?
You wear a rubber suit,then?
那是意外 你知道吗
Accidents happen,you know.
Macy和我是为了挖掘而做了准备 但是谋杀?
Macy and I were prepared for that,but murder?
谋杀 如果有任何我能帮上忙的
Murder. Anything I can do to help...
行 这个我们呆会儿再谈
okay,we'll talk about that a little later.
现在 我要Hodgins下到坑里去
Right now,I want to get hodgins down that shaft.
Dane Mcginnis
Dane mcginnis.
他-据我所知他是最棒的 他为我们工作多年了
He-he's the best i know. he's worked for us for years.
Booth探员? 你是Booth探员吗?
Agent booth?Are you agent booth?
你得呆在黄带外面
You're going to have to stay behind the yellow tape.
我是市长Ney
I'm mayor ney.
你们的人把我们的观光者 推得越来越靠后了
Your men keep pushing our tourists further and further back.
市长? 我- 我希望他们选你的时候 你看来不是这样的
Mayor?I-I hope you didn't look like that when they elected you.
黑胡子的宝藏推动这个小岛的经济向前
Blackbeard's treasure is what keeps the economy on this little island running.
有时候太强了
Sometimes too intensely.
嘿 我并不感到羞愧
Hey,I'm not ashamed.
自我接管政府以来 已经让旅游业上升了63%
I've increased tourism 63% since I took office,
而如果观光客可以凑近点看的话 我可以做的更好
and I can boost it a bit more if the tourists could get a closer look.
它是个谋杀现场 不是场秀
It's a murder scene,not a show.
黑胡子的诅咒
Blackbeard's curse.
Macy也许是想给 自己深爱的小镇一点回报
Macy would've wanted to give a little back to the town that he loved.
Frank 警察告诉他们不可以拍照
Frank,the police are telling them no pictures.
现在 这位是谁呢?海盗皇后? 正确 这是我的太太 Katie
Now,who is this?The pirate queen? That's right.My wife,katie.
好的 听着 你只需要告诉那些游客
That's right. Great.Listen,you just tell the tourists
这里景点不好是诅咒的一部分
that the bad view is part of the curse.
你可以护送这个海盗和他的少妇
Will you please escort the pirate and his wench
到黄线后吗?谢谢
behind the yellow tape?Thank you.
所以 Da--他是个经验丰富的人?
so,da-- he's,an experienced guy?
- 我和上百个合作过 他是最好的 - 好的
I've worked with hundreds.He's the best.--All right.
我希望这个人明白他在做什么
I hope this guy knows what he's doing,
因为下面压力很大
'cause it's tight down there.
太棒了!
Avast,ye lubbers!
Dane 帮他准备好
Dane,let's get him ready.
你认为这是个海盗?
You think it's a pirate?
那是一根300岁男人左手中的手指
It's a 300-year-old finger from the left hand of a male.
这是我所可以肯定的
That's all i'm sure of so far.
值得被杀?
Worth killing for?
我做过一宗一个女人被杀的案件
I worked a case once where a woman was killed,
被肢解和焚烧因为她的朋友
dismembered and burned because her friend thought
认为她拿走了最爱的一双拖鞋
she took favorite pair of slippers.
爽快
Cheery.
或者他们是对的
Maybe they're right.
或者这个男人在藏宝时死了 够讽刺的......
Maybe this man died burying the treasure.Ironic...
偷盗了这么多却没有机会好好享受
stealing all that and never enjoying the spoils.
所以你相信那里有宝藏?
So you believe there's treasure?
我认为那里是贪婪
I believe there's greed.
这是真正的诅咒
That's the real curse.
好的 安全线 氧气管 其中一个断了你都不能回来的
All right,safety line,air hose.Either one breaks,you ain't coming back up.
你得好好学习你的礼貌啊 伙计
You got to work on your bedside manner,dude.
我不想为了那些周末消遣的人负责任
You know,I don't want to be responsible for some weekender
他们下去只是因为他们高估了自己
who buys it down there because he thinks he's better than he is.
你真想下去 是吗?
You want to go down,don't you?
这是我的坑 好吧?
it's my shaft,okay?
我在这里工作已经十年了
I've been working it ten years.
不过联邦调查局的人 他们说这是案发现场 所以我帮不上忙
But the feds-- they say it's a crime scene,so I can't help.
你现在正在帮我
You're helping me.
为什么他还需要氧气管? 为什么他不可以只用氧气筒?
Why's he need the air line?Why can't he just use the tank?
因为在100尺下 坑下会狭小一点
Because around 100 foot down,the shaft gets a little cozy.
你不怕紧迫感 是吧?
You ain't afraid of a tight squeeze,are you,doc?
手套
Gloves.
慢慢来 好啊?
Just take it slow,okay?
在下面有许多东西会缠到氧气管
There's a lot of stuff to catch your hose on on the way down.
我看过Rose拍下的图片
Yeah,I saw the pictures rose took.
Rose 他从未下到你今天要下得 那么深的地方 没有人做过
Rose. He never went as far as you're going.No one has.
也许他只是没有尝试 是呵?
Maybe he shouldn't try,you know?
有人在那下面死 不仅仅Macy
People have died down there,not just macy.
我知道
I know.
我哥哥就是其中一个
My brother was one of them.
我会下到那地方去的 在200尺下?
I'm going all the way down.What's at 200 feet?
我们上个礼拜到的是200尺
We just hit 200 last week.
等你告诉我
You're going to have to tell me.
好的 我准备好了
Well,I'm ready.
好的
Okay.
你朋友最好就像他自己说的那样好
your friend better be as good as he says he is.
你只需要照顾着他 好吧?
You just take care of him,alright?
Hodgins 你能听到我说吗?
Hodgins,you read me?
洪亮清晰
I hear you loud and clear.
Hodgins?
这里很暖
It's warm.
过了第一个洪水瓣
Passing the first flood trap.
我们在那里失去了第一个人
We lost our first man there.
在石灰石下这里有些木头
There's wood here below the limestone.
他对你有意义吗?
Does he make any sense to you?
他过了坑塌下的地方
He's passing the site of the first pit collapse.
在那里下面很紧的
It's tight down here.
这里有很多碎片 我不确定能不能穿过去
There's lots of debris.Not sure I can squeeze through.
嘿 这个人游得像条乌贼
Hey,this guy swims like a squid.
事实上 他游得像个怪物
Actually,he swims like a squint.
什么?不要在意
What? Never mind.
好 现在畅通了
Okay,I'm clear now.
也拍的好照片
Good picture,too.
我们就没有这样的人才
We can't get resolution like that.
他是个为政府工作的人 你没有在下面发现什么东西吗?
he's a geek who works for the government.You ever find anything down here?
还未发现
Not yet.
十年没有发现 而你继续在努力
Ten years of finding nothing,and you keep trying.
过程比较重要 伙计
It's all about the search,man.
他在170尺
He's at 170 feet.
180尺
one-eighty.
190尺
one-ninety.
没有人到这个深度了 他在200尺了
No one's ever been this deep.He's at 200.
碰到下面 我在底部了
Touch down. I am on the bottom.
能见度超乎想象的好啊
Visibility is surprisingly good.
等一下 这里有些东西
Wait a minute.Ere's-there's something here.
那是什么?
what is that?
是不是......
is that...?
老天......
Oh,my god.
这是不是......
Is that...?
对你发现了整副骸骨我很惊讶
I'm amazed you found a complete skeleton.
碳14测试追溯到300年前
C-14 dating matches at 300 years.
这个是男性 20几岁 接近五尺六寸高
Subject is male,early twenties,approximately five feet...six inches.
腿被压弯 因为明显的磷酸钙缺乏
Legs are bowed,result of visible calcium and phosphate deficiency.
他有像孩子一样的软骨病
He had rickets as a child,
但是他的身体却意外地发育良好
but his upper body is extraordinarily well-developed.
骺在长的骨头析出
Epiphyseal separation in the long bones.
消瘦的胸骨在肋骨或肩胛骨旁 形成坏血症的玫瑰花形
Sunken sternum forms scorbutic rosary at costochondral margin.
他患有坏血症 而且有第三期的梅毒
He suffered from scurvy,as well as tertiary syphilis.
什么是第三期? 不是有梅毒就都够糟糕了吗?
What's with the tertiary? Isn't plain all syphilis bad enough?
坏血病 梅毒 海盗
Scurvy,syphilis.Pirate.
有人类学上的证据证明黑胡子
There is anthropological evidence which supports the claim
在完成了挖洞后埋葬了他的人
that blackbeard executed his burial crews after they were done digging.
好的
Okay.
就说这个人是海盗
Let's say it's a pirate.
是的!
Yes!
这会是一个非凡的发现
This would be an extraordinary find.
而且这会公开宝藏的真实情况
And would open up the reality of the treasure.
在这个时候不考虑周全是很愚蠢的
It would be stupid to dismiss anything at this point.
不过我们需要发现为什么骨胶原 没有完全被分解
But we need to discover why the ossein isn't fully decomposed
在水底下这么久
from being waterlogged for so long.
大约在坑50尺下
About 50 feet down the shaft,
有一层由硅和黏土 组成的兰色宝石墨粉
is a layer of blue putty,consisting of silicon and clay.
这可以用来做防水隔离
It can be used to form a watertight seal.
这可以解释骨头的状况
That would explain the condition of the bones.
我拿了些在200-207尺间 同样的兰色黏土样本
I took samples of the same blue clay between 200 and 207 feet.
有些东西埋在那里下面
Something is buried down there.
这些骨头在它们上面放着
And these bones were lying on top of it.
Macy因为他发现这些东西所以被杀了
Macy was killed because of something that he found.
在他喉咙和肺的泥沙确定 他是在竖井顶部被杀的
Silt in his throat and lungs confirms he was killed at the top of the shaft.
在他带着宝藏游上回来后
After he swam back up with the treasure.
Booth探员
Special agent booth.
我讨厌打断你们的调查 Booth探员
I hate to interrupt your investigation,agent booth,
不过有个非常生气的亿万富翁 在我的办公室并且他不离开
but there's an angry billionaire in my office,and he won't go away.
这很简单
It's simple.
你们拥有一些属于我的东西 而我不会离开这里直到我拿回它
You have something that belongs to me,and I'm not leaving here without it.
一天前 你等着要离开
A day ago,you couldn't wait to leave.
从你的岛上撤退 中断你的损失 记得吗?
Pull out of the island,cut your losses.You remember that?
一天内很多事会改变的
A lot can change in a day.
对于Ted Macy 很多事改变了
For ted macy,a lot changed.
我对Ted感到很抱歉 但是我会受谴责如果联邦政府
Look,I'm sorry about ted,but I'll be damned if the federal government
在这里用11个小时抢去和偷去
swoops in here at the eleventh hour and steals
我用了2年的时间去寻找的东西
what I've been trying to find for two years
我没有看到这事和Jeffersonian有关联
I fail to see what this has to do with the jeffersonian.
这些骨头属于我 它们是在我的地方被发现的!
Those bones belong to me.They were uncovered at my site.
我是被授权允许在那里 挖凿和拥有所发现的
I was granted a permit to dig there and keep what was found.
我的律师向我确认 对这些骨头你们没有任何权利拥有
My attorneys assure me,you have no claim to those bones.
如果你的律师想接下来20年到法庭
Sure,I mean,your attorney wants to go to court for the next 20 years,
和给他在Tuscany一个很好的家庭假期
and buy himself a nice vacation home in tuscany,
不过事实是 当Ted Macy被谋杀了
but the fact is,when ted macy was murdered,
你的财产就变成了我们的证据
your property became our evidence.
而且这将会持续到我们发现凶手是谁
And it's going to stay that way until we find the killer.
我原本打算友好地解决的
I was hoping to settle this amicably.
是啊?因为我们直到现在还未发现这点
Really?Because,you know,we haven't seen that yet.
这可能会成为麻烦 他有些很厉害的朋友
This is going to be a headache.He has some very important friends.
我不明白为什么他会这么不开心 看不出来他需要这些钱啊
I don't understand why he's so upset.It's not like he needs the money.
但是他的合作伙伴需要
But he has partners that do.
Macy和Gardewicke 打算分配他们所发现的
Macy and hardewicke were going to split what they found.
但是Macy死了
But macy is dead.
正确 剩下Hardewicke可以分得大块的一份
Exactly. Leaving hardewicke with a bigger piece of the pie.
这是从我们一起发现的第一个挖掘
This is from our very first dig together.
我们发现这些箱在一个新英格兰Simith
we found this-this chest buried under a flood
的洪水退去的小河湾被埋着
drain up in smith's cove in new england.
那里没有宝藏的 但是你知道
There was no treasure,but,you know,
只是在地低下有些很老 有很多历史的东西
just to unearth something that was that old,had that much history--
我们被吸引住了 没有回头过
we were hooked.Never looked back.
我查看了一下你们的公司历史
You know,I glanced through your company history.
生意很呆滞 因为你们在这里 不能找到什么宝藏
I mean,business was pretty slow,since you didn't find any treasure out here.
你们越来越少客户了
You were getting fewer and fewer clients.
这是很困难
it's been difficult.
Branson Rose几乎是你最后一个机会了
Branson rose was almost your last chance.
这里总是有人寻宝的人
There's always somebody who wants to look for treasure.
是吗?
Really?
因为Branson Rose 要退出和拿走很多设施
'Cause,you know,branson rose,he pulls out,and get a lot of publicity,
你们就会结束 就是你们的公司会倒闭
you could end up,you know...Sinking your business.
但是Macy最后发现些东西
but macy found something finally,
我们也会和Rose五五分账 50%归我们
and we're going to share the find with rose-- 50% for him,50 for us.
完全正确
Exactly.
噢 我明白了 如果Macy不在了 我就可以分得多一些是吧?
Oh,I see.More for me if macy's out of the picture,right?
你忘记了一件事 Macy就像是我的家人
You're forgetting one thing.Macy was like family to me.
真的吗?
Really?
看看这个 看到吗?
Look at this. See that?
我在93年因为拉Macy 脱离个流沙洞而得到
I got that pulling macy out of a sinkhole back in '93.
他身上也有很多因为我的伤痕
He's got plenty of scars on him because of me,too.
你是这些痂附近的伤痕怎么得到的?
How'd you get all those bruises around your scar there?
市长
the mayor.
市长是怎么卷进来的?
How does the mayor figure into all this?
他的妻子 你见过她 对吧?
His wife. You saw her,right?
Macy是个有点爱同女人有关系的男人 如果你明白我的意思
Well,macy was a bit of a hound,if you know what I mean.
他和海盗皇后上床?
He was sleeping with the pirate queen?
市长开始怀疑 他上个星期来
The mayor got suspicious,he came around last week,
而我最后保护了Macy
and I ended up taking the heat for macy,
因为Macy就像我的兄弟
because macy's like my brother,
而我要告诉你的是 骨瘦如柴的海盗也会打架的
and I'll tell you,that scrawny little pirate-- hcan kick,too.
幸运的是他没有时间在装弹药
Lucky he didn't have time to load that flintlock.
Charlie? 不是 放下这个 放它在那里 你在干什么?
Charlie?No. Put that down.Leave it there.What are you doing?
Zack? Zack 那些骨头...
Zack?Zack,the bones--
你对那些骨头做什么了?
what did you do with the bones?
没有啊 Brenna教授 我就按你要求的放他们在桌上啊
Nothing,dr. Brennan. I left them on the table just like you asked.
我的骨头在哪里啊?
Where the hell are my bones?
骨头不会无端失踪的 我以为这里有安全机构
bones don't just disappear.I thought is was a secure facility.
你向我保证这里有安全机构的
You assured me this was a secure facility.
你知道我会在斯坦福工作的
I could be working at stanford,you know.
这不会发生在斯坦福的!
This never would have happened at stanford.
我们花了450万在我们的安全设施上
We spend three quarters of a million dollars annually on security.
很明显这个是不够的 我要我的骨头 你找到我的骨头了吗?!
Obviously that's not enough.I want my bones.Did you find my bones?!
或许你会想要 冷静点?
Oh! Maybe you want just want to,you know,chill a little?
冷静?! 你知道 吃点药
Chill?-- You know,take a pill.
听着 伙计 我的实验室被侵入了 我的骨头被偷了
Listen,dude,my lab was violated,my bones were stolen,
因此我认为我会愤怒多一会儿!
so I think I'll remain warm for a little while longer.
- 呼吸 甜心 也许你该注意一下呼吸 - 深呼吸
Honey,maybe you should focus on your breathing.--Breathing.
- 数到十 - 数到十
Count to ten.--Count to ten.
给点行动来
Have a shot of jack.
给点行动 瞧 我们正在做 我们可以做的事情 好吗?
Shot of jack.Look,we're doing everything that we can,okay?
我答应你 我们会找回你的骨头
I promise you,we're going to f find your bone
但是你也必须准许我们做我们的工作
but you have to allow us to do our job.
我想我帮不了什么 对吧?
I guess I wasn't helping all that much,was I?
- 我...... - 对不起......
I...I'M...sorry.
这不要紧
It's cool.
嘿 想积极的一面
Hey,look on the bright side.
这个盗窃会对我们有帮助的 是吗?
I mean,this whole theft thing could be good for us,right?
我的意思是 不管谁偷走了骨头明显地
I mean,whoever took the bones obviously
肯定和凶手有关 我们又近一步了
had something to do with the murder.We're getting closer.
我已经命令所有当时执勤人员
I've ordered all on-duty security personnel to
提交了一份详细到分钟的执勤报告
give a minute-by-minute account of their rounds.
我也同样这样要求了 那些不执勤的人员
I want an account of all off-duty personnel,as well.
他们没有拿走全部
They didn't get everything.
我还认为所有的骨头都已在这台上了
I thought all the bones were on the table.
只有刚发现有坏血病的
All the new ones.
那段我还在检验原始的指骨
I was still examining the original finger bone we found for scurvy,
还在我的房间里
so it was in my room.
有些他们不想我们在这些骨头上 发现的东西
There is something they don't want us to find on these bones.
大家都认识Macy 帮助Frank赢得了选举
Everyone knew macy.Helped frank get elected.
所以你指你们的关系是朋友喽?
So you would categorize your relationship as just friends?
是的 朋友 这是个小镇 大家都是朋友
Friends.It's a small town.We're all friends.
不管怎样 杀了Macy的人 就不是那么友好了
Well,whoever killed macy wasn't too friendly.
他不会伤害任何人--Macy
He wouldn't hurt a soul-- macy.
他是个好人
He was a sweet guy.
从你谈论他的语气看来
The way you're talking about him,
你们不只是朋友吧
it seems like you were more than just friends.
Hardewicke告诉你的? 像是他是个圣人一样
Hardewicke told you,right?Like he's such a saint.
你们两个的关系怎样?
How involved were the two of you?
这只是其中一件事
It was just one of those things,you know.
不管怎样我不会离开Frank的
I wasn't going to leave frank or anything.
我猜我想看到一个名副其实的冒险家
I guess I wanted to see what it was like to be with a real adventurer
而不是一个穿冒险装的人
rather than a guy who dresses up like one.
Frank以为看到了Hardewicke 所以跟了过去
So,frank went after hardewicke when he thought it was him.
你认为Frank杀了他? 你见到过Frank了
You think frank killed him?You saw frank.
你知道 他情绪有点不稳定
Well,You know,he's a little,a little unstable.
当他发现有人耍了他两次时 我
When he finds out somebody made a fool of him twice,I...
你应该注意的是Hardewicke和那个富翁
look,it's hardewicke and the rich guy you should be looking at.
Macy说过他们常常因为分钱不均而吵架
Macy said they were all fighting over the money they were spending.
也说过Hardewicke并不喜欢他做的事
Said hardewicke didn't appreciate all the work he did,
而且想要结束合作关系
wanted to break up the company.
我们-我们正在调查每个人 谢谢
Well,we're-we're looking into everyone.Thanks.
不用谢 但是再提起这些事
Sure.But all this coming up again.
只要不毁了我的婚姻就行了 好吗? 我错过一次
Just try not to ruin my marriage,okay?I made a mistake.
但是我爱那个傻海盗 我不想失去他
But I love that stupid pirate,and I don't want to lose him.
谢谢告诉我这些 我会保持联络的
Well,thanks for talking to me.I'll be in touch.
指骨的骨膜表面没有
The periosteal surface on the phalanx doesn't
我可以还原的根深蒂固的颗粒
have any ingrained particulates that I can recover.
使用M.E.可以溶解任何
The solution that M.E. Used probably dissolved anything
在不规则表面的物质
that was lodged in any surface irregularities.
谁在提取有用信息前洗过这骨头?
Who would clean a bone before extracting all available information from it?
不是每个人都像我们这样专业 Zack
Not everyone is as thorough as we are,zack.
真对 真对
So true,so true.
我希望上面能有金沙呢
I wonder if there was gold dust on it.
也许你应该在你肩上放只鹦鹉 一起工作
Perhaps you should start working with a parrot on your shoulder.
你不好奇吗?
You're not curious?
当然 只对于真相
Yes. About the facts.
在手指的末梢关节面上有个洞
There's a small hole along the distal articular facet of the finger.
那可能是通气孔 也可能是别的 人造的
It could be a foramen,but it could be something else,man-made.
武器?
A weapon?
也许 你看看能不能找到什么吻合的
Maybe.See if you can find any possible matches.
我想知道在Macy身上 会不会有相似的地方?
I wonder if there are any other similar marks on macy?
我会找到的 看牢那段骨头
I'll find out.And don't let that bone out of your sight.
Brennan博士认为你也许能 找到些什么武器之类的东西
Dr. Brennan thought you might have overlooked a weapon of some kind.
他不是被武器打死的 而是被扼死的
he wasn't killed by any weapon.He was strangled.
很明显他的咽喉被压碎了
The larynx is crushed.It's plain.
从c2到c4是断裂的
And c2 through c4 are fractured.
如果他仅仅是被扼死的话 是不会这样的
That wouldn't have occurred if he were merely strangled.
如果受害人被扼住并被摇晃
If the victim was shaken while being strangled...
骨折就会全是从左到右的
the fractures are all left to right,
沿45度角分布在每根骨头上
approximately 45-degree angles on each bone.
那就是说他的头是从左向上被猛扯的
That means the head was jerked to the left and up,
为了让脊椎骨能碎裂
makin sure that the spinal cord would tear.
当他的脖子被折断时 他的咽喉就被压碎了
The larynx was crushed when his neck was broken.
我永远欢迎别人的纠正
I'm always open to being corrected.
你为什么认为会有武器存在
Why do you think there might have been a weapon?
你放进溶液那块骨头上有穿孔
I saw a perforation in the finger bone you put in the solvent.
你用什么东西毁坏过 捅过 刺过骨头吗?
Did you damage the bone,poke it,stick it in some way?
我还是在生气 好吧 没有
Still angry.Okay,no.
我严格遵守守则操作:
I handled it according to protocol:
带着橡胶手套进行溶解
Rubber gloves right into the solvent.
有东西破坏过那骨头 但是在300年内没有过
Something damaged that bone,and it didn't happen 300 years...
等一下
wait a minute.
我想到另一种造成那个洞的可能性
I have alternatives that could have caused the hole.
是一种用于针刺疗法的可任意使用的针
This is a disposable acupuncture needle.
他是在治疗中死亡的?
He was healed to death?
那是一种用于血管重建术的细铁丝
This is a filament used for an angioplasty.
给我那铁丝
Hand me the wire.
- 你在做什么? - 降低荧光性
What are you doing? --Diminished fluorescence.
只有这骨头已经被清洗处理过 它才会变成这样
That only happens if the bones have been cleaned and treated.
- 这些骨头不是源于钻井而是被放在那的 - 什么?
These bones didn't start out in the shaft.They were placed there. What?
谁会有300年的骨头?
Who has got 300-year-old bones?
我保证这所有的东西都是真的 Brennan博士
I assure you everything here is authentic,dr. Brennan.
我自己组织过Jeffersonian的展览
I curated this exhibit for the jeffersonian myself.
你能打开这柜子吗?
Could you please open the case?
这是个非常漂亮的标本
This is a beautiful specimen.
在牙买加被找到的
Found in jamaica.
我相信他和Henry Morgan一起出过海
We believe he sailed with henry morgan.
他一生中从没乘过船
He's never been on a boat in his life.
真可笑
Absurd.
哦 我的天哪
Oh,my god.
这些骨头是人造的 丙烯酸 不是人骨
These bones are artificial.It's acrylic,not bone.
当骨头被重组时 你可以看到
You can see the real hole where the wire was threaded
在铁丝穿过的地方有个洞
when the bones were assembled for display.
我的水手的其他部分在哪?
Then where's the rest of my sailor?
它被转移到了Assateague岛的钻井里
He was planted in the shaft in assateague island
让整个宝藏的传说看起来像真的一样 但是有人找到了
to make the whole treasure business seem real,but somebody found out.
谁?
Who?
一个杀人犯
A murderer.
好吧 让我看看我是否明白了
Okay,let me see if I get this straight.
你还原的海盗的骸骨 是来自Jeffersonian的?
the pirate bones you recovered came from the jeffersonian to start with?
是
Correct.
300年的骨头 在我们自己的海盗展览中被偷了
300-year-old bones stolen from our own pirate exhibit.
然后被你们的人还原了
And then recovered by one of your own people...
Hodgins博士
Dr. Hodgins.
把他们送了回来
...Who brought them back to the jeffersonian,
在那又再次被盗?
where they were stolen again?
再次被盗 先生
Re-stolen,sir.
你有安全上的麻烦 Goodman博士
You have a security problem,dr. Goodman.
当我找到这个小偷时 你可能有杀人上的麻烦了
And when I find out who did this,you may have a murder problem.
但是我在查的 好吗?
But I'm on top of it,okay?
你不用牵扯进来 先生
You didn't have to come down here,sir.
我也这么想直到
That's what I thought,
我接到国防部某人的电话
until I got a call from someone at the department of defense.
国防部? 他们怎么能插手杀人案调查?
Defense? Howo they figure into a murder investigation?
Branson Rose 他在上头有朋友
Branson rose,he has friends in high places,
他们不会想要 那个造轰炸机的家伙不高兴的
and they don't like it when the guy who builds their bombers is unhappy.
他们怕他会炸了他们?
They afraid he'll bomb them?
那算什么 嘲笑吗? 我可没在笑
What is that,squint humor?Because I'm not laughing.
国防部可以不言而战
Defense doesn't need a reason to go to war,
但我不会是他们下一个的目标
and I'm not about to be their next target.
我们追查嫌疑犯有很严格的规定
We have a rude roles out to our suspect.
当然不行了 为了找骨头你们已经很忙了
Well,of course not.You're too busy looking for your bones.
不要把这当成是私事
Let's not make this personal.
如果Rose想要继续趟这潭浑水
Rose wants to keep playing in the mud,
他的大朋友就会来一看究竟
and his big-shot friends are going to see that happens,
除非我们能早一步知道答案
unless we get some answers fast.
在这点上 看起来那些被偷的
At this point,it appears as if
300年的骨头正在被用于
the stolen 300-year-old bones are being used to,
腌制竖井
you know,salt the shaft.
腌制竖井?
Salt the shaft?
投资者花了上百万美元
Yeah,you know,an investor spends a million bucks,
因为什么都没发现时而坐立不安
gets antsy when nothing happens,
然后 哇啦 海盗的骸骨被发现了
and then,voil,you know,pirate bones appear,
就像是金鸡
and the golden goose keeps,you know...
开始生金蛋了
...laying those eggs.
好了 那是很令人费解的比喻 Booth
Okay,that is a convoluted metaphor,booth.
这叫欺骗 Brennan博士 就像是Piltdown的男人
It's a hoax,dr. Brennan,like piltdown man.
哦 知道了 你为什么不能说的那样清楚?
Oh,got it.Why can't you be clear like that?
假设那些骸骨被偷
Assuming the bones were stolen...
再次被偷?
re-stolen?
再次被偷 那你不可能发现他们是假的 你是怎么做到的?
...Re-stolen so you wouldn't find out they were bogus,how did you?
我怎么做什么了?
How did I what?
从指骨上得知的 他们没有拿到整个的骸骨
From the finger. They didn't get the entire skeleton.
你愿意让Brennan博士讲一下过程吗?
Would you like dr. Brennan to take you through the process?
我实在 实在是不想 那你认为是谁?
I really,really wouldn'T.So who do you like?
我想是拍档
I like the partner.
Giles Hardewicke 出入自由 动机 能力
Giles hardewicke.Access,motive,ability...
Goodman博士 FBI会提供
dr. Goodman,the fbi will provide
一切帮你解决Jeffersonian的安全问题
whatever help you need to solve your breach of security at the jeffersonian.
你有合伙人了
You work the partner angle.
我父亲在渔船上工作 他的父亲以前也是
Well,my father worked a fishing boat,his dad before that.
Heck 我和我哥哥 除了大海我们对其他一无所知
Heck,me and my brother,we never knew anything but the sea.
我想我会找到宝藏
Hunting for treasure just sort of grew out of that I guess.
后悔了吗?
Any regrets?
是的 我哥哥
Sure. My brother.
还有他们可以让我们关门这个事实
that and the fact they might shut us down.
嘿 除非我们找到什么
Hey,not if we find something.
我还以为你会回到办公室变回
You know,I thought you were going to turn out to be just another desk jockey
那种读点书
who'd read a few books and was
找些东西可以打发无聊生活的人
looking for something to brighten up his boring-ass life.
我来告诉你 我现在就想再下去一次
I'll tell you what,I'd be down that shaft right now
如果我有更多时间潜水的话
if big brother didn't have a minimum time requirement between dives.
你来这来对了 真的
you deserve to be here.you really do.
谢谢了 伙计
Thanks for that,man.
实话和你说 那些骨头是被转移过来的
as true as i tell you,The bones were planted.
你看起来并不惊讶
you don't seem surprised.
没有什么让我吃惊 在钻井里见多了
nothing surprises me out of that ... pit anymore.
只要你挖的够深 你就能到地狱了
I mean,you dig down far enough,you'll come out in hell.
如果你没有发现什么 你会让我们关门吗?
So,if you don't find anything,are you gonna shut us down?
我不是FBI 我只是个科学家
I'm not fbi.I'm just a scientist.
这里是犯罪现场
It's a crime scene.
我很惊讶他们让你下来
I'm surprised they let you down there.
我是泥沙 植物和昆虫方面的专家--
I'm an expert in silt,plants,and insects--
对哦
that's right.
我拿到了三个博士头衔
I got three doctorates.
当你拿到三个博士头衔的时候 你告诉FBI你需要更多的样本
When you got three doctorates,and you tell the fbi you need more samples,
谁会怀疑? 一个 也许会 但三个呢?
who's gonna argue?One doctorate,maybe they argue,but three?
你想要再回去一次吗?
you want to go back down again,don't you?
我需要你的帮助 伙计
I could use your help,man.
你真喜欢潜水啊 伙计!
You got the bug,man!
嘿 就像我说的 我是虫男
Hey,like I said,I am the bug man.
如果你丢了那些骨头 你怎么知道它们是假的?
If you lost the bones,how do you know they're fake?
小偷 他们没有拿走全部
Thieves,they didn't get everything.
那些好人走运了
Stroke of luck for the good guys.
我们会找出那些骨头
We will find out
是怎样从Jeffersonian那被偷的
how those bones were stolen from the jeffersonian.
你还是认为是我做的 是吗?
You still think i did it,don't you?
你为什么要拆伙?
Why were you going to break up the company?
让我猜猜 Katie Ney告诉你的?
let me guess,katie ney tell you that?
你为什么会想到是Katie?
What makes you think it was katie?
那就是Macy调情的技巧所在 那非常有效
That was a stock part of macy's seduction technique,and it was very effective.
"我在那洞里出生入死 而我的同伴却稳稳的高高在上"
"I risk my life down in that hole while my partner stays safe topside."
那就是他怎样把自己 塑造的像个英勇的冒险家的
That's how he positioned himself as the heroic explorer...
事实上他是的 顺便提一下 当是对女人的时候
which he was,by the way,when it came to the ladies.
你的关系牢靠吗?
Your partnership was intact?
只有死亡可以分开我们
Till death did us part.I'll tell you what.
我给你们所有你们要的所有通行许可
I'm gonna give you guys full access to the books.
你们甚至不需要搜查证
You don't even need a search warrant.
没有Macy的日子每一天我都很难过
There's not a single way in which my life is tter off without macy.
像我说的 我想念那家伙
Like I said,I miss the man.
那些骨头被偷了两次--
the bones were stolen twice--
第一次是在海盗展上
the first time from the pirate exhibit,
第二次是在这的法医试验室里
the second from the bone room here in the medico-legal lab.
试验室的监控是很紧密的 所以摄像机一直在工作
The security in the lab is tighter,so the camera is continuous,
但是在圆形大厅里的会每三秒停一次
but the camera in the rotunda is stop-action,every three seconds.
我从试验室的那次查起
I started with the lab theft
因为我们都知道骨头是在9p.m.到6a.m.之间被偷的
because we know the bones were stolen between 9 P.M.And 6 A.M.
好吧 看 这里
Okay.Watch... here.
骨头不见了
The bones are gone.
注意时间条码
Notice the time-code.
那是什么?
What's that?
摄影机被关了
The camera was turned off.
摄像机停了1分46秒
Camera was turned off for one minute and 46 seconds.
这个时间足够进屋
It would take a lot less time that
收集尸骨然后逃跑了
to enter the room and gather up the bones and escape.
现在
Now...
Goodman博士?
dr. Goodman?
什么?
Yes?
我能不能问一下 为什么我们 而不是保安来做这个调查?
Could I ask,why are we doing this investigation instead of security?
我们不能走的太快；
We shouldn't walk too quickly;
会引起怀疑的 也不想引起小偷的注意
it would arouse suspicion.Neither would our thief.
我很乐意帮忙 但是我们确实拥有 真正的安全专家们 他们
I'm happy to help,but we do have actual security professionals who...
有方法分辨出哪些带子是修改过的?
is there any way to tell if those tapes have been doctored?
有啊 因为那些是物理磁带 而不是数码储存数据
Since they're physical magnetic tapes,not stored digitally.
我更喜欢模拟数据 现在我知道原因了
I always did like analog better.Now,I know why.
我的意思是我对这方面只是业余水平
My point is is that I'm only an amateur at this,
并且 我相信安全部门在这方面
and I'm sure the security department
有更好的装备 也更加训练有素
is better equipped and trained...
下午好 Paul 问Susan和Laura好
afternoon,paul.Best to susan and laura.
希望Johnny好点儿了
I hope johnny feels better.
好吧 你不想谈这个 明白了
Okay you don't want to talk about it.I get it.
长官?
Sir?
按一下你的秒表 Montenegro女士
Hit your stopwatch,please,ms. Montenegro.
35.6 秒
35.6 seconds.
一个来回是这个时间的双倍 就是1分10秒
Double that for a round-trip.That's one minute,ten seconds,
离开大约30秒 装下尸骨然后回去
leaving approximately 30 seconds to bag the bones and get back.
回哪里?
Get back where?
你肯定以为我是个白痴
you must think i'm an idiot.
旁观者清 我也可以像你一样
I was grandstanding.I can be like that.
我们发现了这两宗盗窃发生的时候 保安还在值班
So we find out what guards were on duty during the two thefts
或许是我们这有内贼
and we might have our thief.
我没偷Hummy
I don't steal the Hummy.
偷窃尸骨?
In stealing human remains?
300年后 他好像不会有一个家庭成员
After 300 years,it's not like he's got
在那里为他的死而悲痛欲绝
a family grieving for him out there.
可以想象我是一个悲痛的家长
Think of me as a grieving parent.
重大盗窃案 老兄 你已经等了8年了
Grand theft,buddy;you're looking at eight years.
如果我没杀你
If I don't kill you.
少来了 一堆这样的旧尸骨能值多少?
Come on,what's a bunch of old bones like that worth?
一文不值
Nothing.
你得到了多少?
How much you get for them?
几百块
Couple of hundred bucks.
这个小偷在你户头上转入了1万块 是什么 遗产?
So this wire transfer into your bank for ten grand,what's that,inheritance?
你为谁偷窃?
Who did you steal them for?
我们不做姓名交易
We didn't really do the name-exchange thing.
有人接近过你?
Somebody approached you?
我们看看 好吧 是哪个?
Let's see. Okay.Which one was it?
哪一次?
Which time?
第一次
The first time.
他 但是他真人比照片好看多了
Him...but he looked better.
第二次呢?
And the second time?
他
him.
看 伙计们 我合作 行吗?
Look,guys,I'm cooperating,all right?
我把钱还给你们 我辞职不干了 行吗?
I will give back the money.I will quit my job,all right?
我们公平交易怎么样?
How's about we just call it even?
我们叫地方检察官怎么样?
How's about we call the D.A.?
你知道 你们需要在博物馆 设立更好的监视程序
You know,you need a better screening process down at the museum.
真是讽刺 何不把你的提议交给FBI
Ironic,given we contract that out to the fbi.
你认为他很危险?
You think he's dangerous?
重大盗窃案 谋杀
Grand theft,murder,
有音乐
the music.
他在下面
He's down there.
那不是音乐 是风笛
That's not music,it's bagpipes.
Harde先生
Mr. Harde...
或许我们要找的是别人
Maybe we're looking for someone else.
喉管被压碎了
the larynx was crushed.
那就是你的死因规律?
Is that going to be your cause-of-death ruling?
关于这个我们要再吵一架?
We gonna have another fight about this?
我是非常宽容的 但是如果你一直这样自以为是
I'm a pretty open guy,harry,but if you keep pushing like that,
把你喉管压碎的将会是我
it's gonna be me who smacks you around.
你怎么知道你来这套就对我管用呢?
How do you know that won't work for me just as well?
你推断Macy死于喉管压碎
You ruled that macy died from a crushed larynx.
压碎喉管是致命的 因此导致死亡
A crushed larynx is fatal,ergo it results in death.
你之前错了 现在也错了
You were wrong then,and you're wrong now.
看到没?他喜欢这样
See? He likes it.
我想看他和Macy的X光片
I need to see both sets of x rays,his and macy'S.
并不总是对和错的问题
It's not always about being right or wrong.
是对话的问题
It's about the dialogue.
一场激烈的谈话 可以是一种非常好的交流
An intense conversation can be the most wonderful kind of intercourse.
知道吗?这家伙是个变态
Know what?This guy is a pervert.
c-2和c-4之间伤害 45度角
Damage between c-2 and c-4,45 degree angle,
和Macy的被害模式一样
exact same pattern of injury as macy.
他的头被转了一圈 可能另一只手在压喉管
His head was wrenched around,probably while the other hand crushed the larynx.
我弄错了一定让你很不爽
That must really frustrate you that I missed that.
那是特种部队的行为方式
That's a special forces move.
把守卫撂倒 压碎喉管 所以喊不出声
Take a sentry down,crush the larynx,so he can't scream.
你做过?
You've done that to people?
不是 我们的凶手是个特种兵
No. Our murderer is special forces.
你的Inter网简历说你曾在 英国空军特种部队待过一段时间
Your internet bio says you spent time in special air services.
Rose先生的生活丰富多彩
Mr. Rose has led a diverse and full life.
当你发现那个采掘地被保护起来后 有什么感觉?
How did you feel when you found out the dig site had been salted?
当然 我很失望
I was disappointed,certainly.
只是失望?
Just disappointed?
我还没烦到杀了Ted macy行了吧
Look,I wasn't irked enough to kill ted macy.
现在 我们说重点吗?
Now,could we get to the point,please?
什么是英国空军特种部队?
What is special air services?
普遍认为 英国空军特种部队是世界上
The S.A.S. Is widely regarded as one of the
最杰出 最训练有素的一支特种部队
finest and best trained special forces units in the world.
行动过吗?
See any active service?
Rose先生对讨论细节不太感冒
Mr. Rose is not comfortable discussing specifics.
我不希望以好人的性命为代价
I don't like to exploit my role in operations
来发挥我在军事行动中的作用
which cost good men their lives.
好吧 如果你们都对我过去的经历感兴趣
Now,if all you're interested in is my history,
那全在我网上的简历上
there's a bio on my web site.
太好了 我们只是想知道你的名声 是不是真的 先生
Great.We just want to know if your reputation is for real,sir.
我们只要联系英国空军特种部队就行了 他们会说的
Hey,we'll just contact the S.A.S.They'll tell us.
好吧
Look...fine.
别指望快速回复
Don't expect a speedy response.
Bones
bones.
那是人身攻击!
That's assault!
一个特种兵 有没有可能阻止我刚才的行为?
Would a special forces guy have been able to stop that?
我不清楚 你刚才好像是扑向他那边
I don't know,you kind of got the jump on him there.
这次可不会是个突袭了
This one won't be a surprise.
准备好了吗?
You ready?
什么?
What?
这是粗俗的人身攻击!你们得赔偿!
This is common assault!Charges will be laid!
他不可能是特种兵 那是胡说八道
No way he's special ops.It's just pr crap.
好吧 没问题了
All right,no more questions.
我要求以人身侵犯罪逮捕她!
I demand she be arrested for assault!
闭嘴 Kendall
Shut up,kendall.
我把这女的送上法庭 因为她抽了我耳光?
That I'm taking a woman to court for slapping me?
走吧 我们离开这儿吧
Come on,let's get out of here.
你不会因为这个有麻烦吗?
You won't get into trouble for this?
三级谋杀
Three degrees.
我告诉你了 不管是真是假 那个竖井底部有一些东西
I'm telling you,salted or not,there's something at the bottom of that shaft.
永远别不到黄河不死心
Never got to go all the way down.
那尸骨在木头上放着
The bones were laying on wood.
我想看看那底下是什么
I want to see what's underneath.
从来都觉得找到它的人应该是我
Always thought it'd be me who'd find it.
嘿 人人为我 我为人人 不是吗?
Hey,all for one d one for all,right?
他们对于我来说都是海盗之类
they were always pirate-y to me.
我们开始吧
Let's do this.Let's do it.
好的
Okay.
紧急通讯 22705
Dispatch,22705.
姓:Mcginnes；名:Dane 中间名首字母:P
Last name: Mcginnis; first name:Dane; middle initial: P.
我需要知道他服役于哪支部队
I need to know which branch of the military he served in.
收到 22705 待命
Affirmative,22705.Stand by.
为什么是Dane?
Why dane?
他说Hodgins游起来像鱿鱼
He said hodgins swam like a squid.
怪物 他说的一定是怪物
Squint.He must have said "squint."
对 我说的是怪物 行吗?
No,I said "squint," okay?
Dane说的是乌贼 这是水兵的军事用语
Dane said "squid," which is military slang for a sailor.
这就是他们所谓的万福玛利亚通行证?
Is this what they call a hail mary pass?
你在接收吗?
You receiving?
洪亮清晰
Loud and clear.
老兄 今天的泥真多
Man,it's muddy today.
通常在12米初要清理过去的 第一个洪水通道
Usually clears up past the first flood channel at 12 meters.
还有一瓶朗姆酒呢
Yo-ho-ho and a bottle of rum.
可别把鬼魂召来了 博士
Don't conjure up any ghosts,doc.
底下太多了 等着找你呢
There's too many down there already waiting to claim your ass.
鬼魂 是啊
Ghosts.Right.
22705 紧急通讯
22705,dispatch.
Mcginnis Dane 在海军服役过
Mcginnis,dane,served in the navy.
军衔:军士长 海军特殊战争
Rating: Chief petty officer,naval special warfare.
肯定是
Had to be.
什么?
What?
这家伙是一名海军陆战队员
Guy was a navy seal.
所以?你是个向导
So? You were a guide.
突击队员 我曾是个突击队员 Bones 行吗?
A ranger. I was a ranger,bones,okay?
我不是个向导
I was not a guide.
向导 他们带你看瀑布 他们卖饼干给你 我是个突击队员
Guides,they show you waterfalls,they sell you cookies.I was a ranger.
他在竖井那干嘛?
What's he doing at the shaft?
突击队员害怕海军陆战队员吗?
Are rangers afraid of seals?
什么?少来了 Bones 不 突击队员谁都不怕
What? Come on,bones,no.Rangers aren't afraid of anybody.
行吗?虽然海军陆战队员也很棒
All right?Seals are pretty good,though.
Dane
dane.
怎么了?
What's up?
我们知道是你
We know it was you.
Bones 算了吧
Bones,please...
怎么了?你有枪 他有什么?
Why? You have a gun.What's he got?
他在竖井下有一个人
He's got somebody in the shaft.
我潜了多深?
How far down am I?
那是Hodgins吗?
Is that hodgins?
我看不见深度显示 有什么事吗?
I can't read my depth display.is something going on?
上面有人吗?怎么不回答我?
Is there anybody up there?Why don't you answer me?
Cpo Mcginnis 离开那个通气管
Cpo mcginnis,step away from the air hose.
我需要你把枪扔到竖井这来
Well,I need you to toss that gun into the shaft.
然后 把你的钥匙扔过来
Then,toss me your keys.
然后 把自己铐在那台起重机上 我开走你的卡车
Then,handcuff yourselves to that crane.I take your truck.
否则 我就切断这根管子 让你朋友去死
Otherwise,I am gonna cut this hose,and your buddy's gonna die.
照他说的做吧
do that.
Bones 那不可能发生
Bones.Not gonna happen.
我感觉到一股冷水
Feel a blast of cold water.
要么是泉水 要么是海水中的一种涌泉
Either a spring or some kind of conduit from the ocean.
这是很清澈的水 可见度更高
It's clear,clean water,so visibility is better.
你杀了两个人 我不可能让你开车逃走的
You killed two men.I can't just let you drive away.
那些人
Those guys...
把假尸骨放那里 把整个事件变成了一个骗局
putting fake bones in there,making the whole thing into a con job.
我的兄弟为了寻找宝藏死在那下面 很多好人也都死了
My brother died down there looking for that treasure,lot of good men did.
这就是他们的命 这些人不尊重他们
This was their life.Those men dishonored them.
Dane 你能听到我吗 老兄?我在水底
Dane,can you hear me,man?I am on the bottom.
在我切断这个同期管之前
You good enough to take that shot
你能足够准确的射中我吗 突击队员?
before I cut this air hose,ranger?
会很准
Pretty good.
只是很准?
Just pretty good?
拜托 我在努力了
Please,I'm working.
下面看起来像含沙的肥土 可能有些黏土 我取些样本
Looks like a sandy loam down,maybe a little clay.I'll get a sample.
我能看见以前竖井的围墙倒塌的地方
I can see where the shaft walls collapsed before.
噢 我的天
Oh,my god.
Holy 你能看见这个吗 Dane?
Holy...can you see this,dane?
是什么?
What is it?
你为什么不看看?
Why don't you take a look?
我看了你会开枪的
I do,you'll shoot me.
Dane!你能看见这个吗?老兄?!
dane!Can you see this,man?!
是枚金币
It's a gold coin.
这可能是他们从你的博物馆偷来的 扔到那里的
it's probably something else they stole from your museum and threw in there.
这是真的!这是大 !
This is real!It's a big...!
你想看 就得把Hodgins拉上来
you want to see it,you're going to have to bring hodgins up.
求你了 他在下面是因为他相信
Please.He's down there because he believes.
他和你没什么不同 和你兄弟也没什么不同
He's no different than you,no different than your brother.
把他拉上来
Bring him up.
为了你兄弟 拉他上来吧
Do it for your brother.
原始的褐绿色984.5西班牙古金币 以色列石匠设计
An original breen 984 half doubloon,designed by ephraim brasher,
雕刻 并且
engraved by ephraim brasher,and,
屏住呼吸 女士们先生们 204格令(约为0.466盎司)
hold your breath,gentlemen and ladies,204 grains.
真的海盗金币
A real,gold,pirate coin.
那下面还有多少?
How many more are down there?
Branson Rose已经同意
Branson rose has agreed
等这些宝藏全捞上来后
to have the museum do the authentication
博物馆来为整个宝藏做鉴定
of the entire treasure when they bring it up.
不会再有了
There won't be any more.
你为什么这么说?
What makes you say that?
我下去过
I was down there.
不要这么轻易放弃
It's not gonna give it up that easily.
但是 这个宝藏已经被找到了
But the treasure's been located.
而且 我肯定以前也被找到过
And I'm sure it's been located before.
我来保管这个
I'll take that.
你觉得会开心的回家吗?
You think he's happy to be back home?
我觉得他会这样
Well,he looks that way to me.
他不开心
He's not happy.
你什么意思?
What do you mean?
Hodgins是对的
Hodgins is right.
他在竖井底下的时候更开心
He'd be a lot happier at the bottom of that shaft.
和那些海盗一起
With the other pirates.
兄弟!
matey!
啊! 啊 兄弟!
Arr! Arr,matey!